Remember her name.
Cabrini is a history, drama film directed by Alejandro Monteverde.
Italian immigrant Francesca Cabrini arrives in 1889 New York City and is
greeted by disease, crime, and impoverished children.
Cabrini sets off on a daring mission to convince the hostile mayor to
secure housing and healthcare for society's most vulnerable.
With broken English and poor health, Cabrini uses her entrepreneurial mind to
build an empire of hope unlike anything the world had ever seen.
Francesca Cabrini, played by Cristiana Dell'Anna.
Archbishop Corrigan, played by David Morse.
Pope Leo XIII, played by Giancarlo Giannini.
Mayor Gould, played by John Lithgow.
Vittoria, played by Romana Maggiora Vergano.
Paolo, played by Federico Ielapi.
Cabrini is a 2024 American biographical drama film directed by Alejandro Gómez
Monteverde and written by Rod Barr, based on a story by both.
The film depicts the life of Catholic missionary Francesca Cabrini, portrayed by Cristiana Dell'Anna,
as she encounters resistance to her charity and business efforts in New York City.
Cabrini explores the sexism and anti-Italian bigotry faced by Cabrini
and others in New York City in the late 19th century.
Cabrini was released in the United States on March 8, 2024, by Angel Studios.
The film received mostly positive reviews, yet became a box-office bomb,
grossing $20.6 million worldwide on a $50 million budget.
The film explores themes of new york city, immigrant,
based on true story, 19th century, somber.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.